Guide to the Carolee Schneemann Papers M1892
Department of Special Collections and University Archives
- Series 4. Correspondence, 1949-2011
  - Naomi Levinson to CS, 1958 (Box 109, Folder 4)
  - Naomi Levinson to CS, 1959 (Box 109, Folder 5)
  - Naomi Levinson to CS, 1960, 1962 (Box 109, Folder 6)
  - Naomi Levinson- letters from others [Larry Jordan, Frederick Rzewski (dated mutal friend Elsa), 1960, 1962 (Box 109, Folder 7)
  - CS to Naomi Levinson [annotated photocopies], 1956-1060 (Box 76, Folder 3)
  - CS to parents, 1958-1965 (Box 76, Folder 4)
  - 1960s (Box 76, Folder 5)
  - 1970s (Box 76, Folder 6)
  - 1980s (Box 76, Folder 7)
  - 1991-1992 (Box 76, Folder 8)
  - Joan Hotchkis, 1993-1995 (Box 76, Folder 9)
  - 1994 (Box 76, Folder 10-11)
  - 1995 (Box 77, Folder 1-2)
  - 1996 (Box 77, Folder 3-5)
  - 1996 (Box 78, Folder 1)
  - 1997 (Box 78, Folder 2)
  - 1998 (Box 79, Folder 1-2)
  - 1999 (Box 79, Folder 3-5)
  - 1999 (Box 80, Folder 1)
  - 2000 (Box 80, Folder 2-5)
  - 2001 (Box 81, Folder 1-4)
  - Jim Schaeffer, 2001-2005 (Box 81, Folder 5)
  - Melissa Moreton, 1999-2001 (Box 81, Folder 6)
  - Joe Berke, 1994-2002 (Box 82, Folder 1)
  - 2002 (Box 82, Folder 2-6)
  - 2002 (Box 83, Folder 1)
  - 2003 (Box 83, Folder 2-4)
  - 2004 (Box 83, Folder 5)
  - 2004 (Box 84, Folder 1-2)
  - 2005 (Box 84, Folder 3-4)
  - 2006 (Box 84, Folder 5)
  - 2006 (Box 85, Folder 1-2)
  - 2007 (Box 85, Folder 3-5)
  - 2008 (Box 86, Folder 1-3)
  - 2009 (Box 86, Folder 4-5)
  - Schaeffer political email, 2009 (Box 86, Folder 6)
  - 2010 (Box 87, Folder 1-2)
  - 2011 (Box 87, Folder 3-4)
  - postcards, 1950s (Box 87, Folder 5)
  - postcards, 1960s (Box 87, Folder 6)
  - postcards, 1970-1973 (Box 88, Folder 1)
  - postcards, 1974-1975 (Box 88, Folder 2)
  - postcards, 1976-1977 (Box 88, Folder 3)
  - postcards, 1978-1979 (Box 88, Folder 4)
  - postcards, 1980-1981 (Box 88, Folder 5)
  - postcards, 1982-1983 (Box 88, Folder 6)
  - postcards, 1984-1986 (Box 88, Folder 7)
  - postcards, 1987-1989 (Box 89, Folder 1)
  - christmas cards, 1980s (Box 89, Folder 2)
  - christmas cards, 1990s (Box 89, Folder 3-5)
  - christmas cards, 2000s (Box 90, Folder 1)
- Series 4. Writing
  Notes, dream journals, and other unpublished writing by Schneemann. Notebooks, artist books, scrapbooks and publications have been gathered in other series.
  - articles, notes, correspondence, etc. (Box 190, Folder 10)
  - Personal Notes [M23], 1963-2000 (Box 28, Folder 4-5)
    Various bits of diary, memoir, dream journal, drafts of letters. Mixed holograph and typescript with holograph additions, revisions, approx. 200pp.
  - Spirit Work [P1] (Box 28, Folder 6)
    Approximately 30 pages of holograph notes and correspondence regarding communication with animals.
  - Kitch Notes [P2] (Box 28, Folder 7)
    Approximately 20 images of Kitch, as well as approximately 100 pages of collected typescript with moderate holograph revisions.
  - Essay - Ages of the Avant Garde [E1], 1994 (Box 28, Folder 10)
    Computer-generated typescript with holograph corrections, 10pp.
  - Essays [E4] (Box 28, Folder 11)
    Typescripts and computer-generated typescripts, much with holograph revision, of various essays, lectures, articles, stories, approx. 1250pp.
  - Dreams, 1960s-1990s (Box 42, Folder 5)
  - Dreams/dreamwork (Box 42, Folder 6)
  - Dream/Space/Object, Death/Mother/Bird (Box 42, Folder 7)
  - Dreams/Notes, 1980s-1990s (Box 42, Folder 8)
  - Documentaries, 1980s-1990s (Box 43, Folder 9)
  - misc. notes (Box 43, Folder 6-7)
  - Lebanon series, other notes (Box 43, Folder 8)
  - Cluny Sailor + Animal (Box 43, Folder 4)
  - Cats dreams notes, 1994 (Box 43, Folder 2)
  - Dreams notes, 1996-1997 (Box 43, Folder 3)
  - Notes & dreams, 1988-1990 (Box 43, Folder 1)
  - Does Kristine [Stiles] Have (Box 44, Folder 4)
  - misc. notes, writing, etc. (Box 44, Folder 1-2)
  - Letters - Activist (Box 44, Folder 10)
  - Story- Essays (Box 44, Folder 8)
  - Color Money Book MIT (Box 44, Folder 7)
  - Aging & Avant-Garde, 1992-1993 (Box 44, Folder 9)
  - Video Book - Edit, 1980 (Box 44, Folder 6)
  - Early Background [dreams etc.] (Box 44, Folder 5)
  - Schaeffer research [house] (Box 45, Folder 8)
  - misc. notes (Box 45, Folder 10)
  - Notations/Dreams, 2002-2007 (Box 90, Folder 3)
  - Type In [misc. notes], 1980s-1990s (Box 110, Folder 1)
  - Notes [mostly re: sex & gender] (Box 110, Folder 2)
  - Selected Notes [copies], 1954-1964 (Box 110, Folder 3)
  - Dean Rolston memorial (Box 110, Folder 4)
  - Sketches With Process Notation (Box 110, Folder 5)
  - Projects - Proposals (Box 110, Folder 6)
  - Process Notes [clippings], 1992-1995 (Box 110, Folder 7)
  - Lecture Art - Life [notes] (Box 110, Folder 8)
  - Morphologies (Box 111, Folder 1)
  - Dreams - Notations (Box 111, Folder 3)
  - Sexuality [notes] (Box 111, Folder 4)
  - Vulva Morphia research (Box 111, Folder 5)
  - Notes, 1960s (Box 111, Folder 10)
  - Notes, 1970s (Box 111, Folder 11)
  - Notes, 1980s (Box 111, Folder 12)
  - writing/notes/dreams [includes some school notes & papers], undated, 1954-1975 (Box 124, Folder 1)
  - personal notes, 2002-2005 (Box 124, Folder 2)
  - personal notes, 2006 (Box 124, Folder 3)
- Series 5. Notebooks, scrapbooks, sketchbooks, artist books, art
  Schneeman writing and artwork mostly in bound form, both published and unpublished. Includes class notes, draft correspondence, collage, and childhood drawings and sketches. Notebooks contain sketches, dreams, ideas and other notes, addresses, to-do lists, and collage, and are arranged chronologically in a subseries. Self-published limited edition books (numbered in a "B" series originally) are also described as a subseries.
  - Subseries 5.1. Notebooks
    These notebooks (many hand-decorated) document Schneemann's projects and travels,and functioned as address books, daily planners, diaries, and sketch pads. They have been sorted chronologically, but some notebooks have content from other years as well.
    - loose sketches and notes in folder, 1949-1955 (Box 133, Folder 3)
    - Papers Bard/Wayne [Battelle], 1953-1954 (Box 133, Folder 1)
      College notes, sketches, other notes, drafts. Also includes letters from boyfriend.
    - Summer 53, 1953-1957 (Box 133, Folder 2)
      Notes, sketches, teaching notes from Bennington YMCA, Bard course list, 1957 notes, New School For Social Research grades 1954, Wayne Batelle correspondence drafts. Some notes not by CS.drafts
    - London Notebooks 1-7 (Box 244)
    - London Notebooks 8-14 (Box 245)
    - London Notebooks 15-20 (Box 246)
    - 1981-1990 (Box 129, Folder 1)
    - 1991-1994 (Box 129, Folder 2)
    - 1994-1995 (Box 129, Folder 3)
    - 1995-1996 (Box 130, Folder 1)
    - 1997 (Box 130, Folder 2)
    - 1998 (Box 130, Folder 3)
    - 1998-2000 (Box 131, Folder 1)
    - 2000-2001 (Box 132, Folder 2)
    - 2001-2002 (Box 132, Folder 3)
    - 2003-2004 (Box 132, Folder 4)
    - 2005-2006 (Box 132, Folder 5)
      - unlabeled notebook with gold painted cover (Box 141)
        Pasted in photographs of CS paintings, installations etc.
  - Subseries 5.2. Numbered books
    - The Lebanon Series: War Mop [B4], 1983 (Box 140, Folder 4)
      Magazine produced in conjunction with an exhibit at the Max Hutchinson Gallery, September 10-October 8, 1983.
    - Boca Ratan - Rat Mouth [B1], 1982 (Box 140, Folder 1)
      Journal with clippings, sketches, poems and personal notes.
    - Cezanne She Was A Great Painter. The Second Book [B2], January 1975 (Box 140, Folder 2)
    - Parts of A Body House Book; American I Ching Apple Pie [B3], January 1972 (Box 140, Folder 3)
    - Video Burn, SFAI [B6], 1992 (Box 140, Folder 5)
      Book published in conjunction with the 1991 exhibition from the drawing sequence Video Burn (1987-1991). Has ISBN.
  - Subseries 5.3. Diaries [RESTRICTED]
    - 1953-1963 (Box 162)
      Conditions Governing Access
      Diaries are CLOSED for research until five years after Schneemann's death.
    - 1964-1969 (Box 163)
    - 1970-1973 (Box 164)
    - 1974-1977 (Box 142)
    - 1978-1980 (Box 165)
    - 1981-1984 (Box 166)
    - 1985-1988 (Box 167)
    - 1989-1992 (Box 168)
    - 1993-1996 (Box 169)
    - 1997-2000 (Box 170)
    - 2001-2004 (Box 171)
    - 2005-2007 (Box 172)
  - Subseries 5.4. Life Books [B/N #94]
    Five bound scrapbooks, folio sized, approximately 70pp per volume. These scrapbooks are an "endurance piece," spanning from the early 1960s until approximately 1978 or 1979, with an additional unumbered and partially finished volume from the 1980s.
    - Life Book #1, c.1920s-late 1950s (Box 135)
      Photo scrapbook, some annotations. Many family photos, James Tenney, Stan & Jane Brakhage, etc. Very fragile, some pages torn, some photos missing.
    - Life Book #2 (Box 136)
    - Life Book #3 (Box 137)
    - Life Book #4, August 1973-December 1979 (Box 138)
    - Life Book, 1980s (Box 139)
      Not originally numbered. Also includes loose material likely intended for scrapbooing.
  - Subseries 5.5. Juvenalia
    - Childhood Drawings - Sketchbooks [A6] (Box 133, Folder 4-5)
      CS was around 5 or 6 years old when she made these drawings. There is also one notebook here labeled "1966-67 French Excercises & Notes"
    - Teen Drawings [A6], 1948-1949 (Box 140, Folder 9)
    - Childhood Drawings [A6] (Box 140, Folder 8)
  - Subseries 5.6. Art
    - misc. artwork, collage, etc. (oversize) (Box 157, Folder 5)
    - The High Priestess (Tarot) collage [M21], 1995 (Box 140, Folder 6)
    - Cat Scan & Ask the Goddess material [A5], 1987-1991 (Box 29, Folder 2-3)
      Drawings and text for Cat Scan and Ask the Goddess. Approx. 22 drawings and 50pp text most on large index cards.
- Series 6. Writing on Schneemann
  Articles, reviews, interviews, essays, theses, etc. concerning Schneemann. Arrangement is chronological, with oversized items filed separately.
  - Subseries 6.1. chronological
    - 1963 (Box 52, Folder 1)
    - 1964 (Box 52, Folder 2)
    - 1965 (Box 52, Folder 3)
    - 1966 (Box 52, Folder 4)
    - 1967 (Box 52, Folder 5)
    - 1968 (Box 52, Folder 6)
    - 1969 (Box 52, Folder 7)
    - 1970 (Box 52, Folder 8)
    - 1971 (Box 52, Folder 9)
    - 1972 (Box 52, Folder 10)
    - 1973-1974 (Box 52, Folder 11)
    - 1975 (Box 52, Folder 12)
    - 1976 (Box 52, Folder 13)
    - 1977 (Box 53, Folder 1)
    - 1978 (Box 53, Folder 2)
    - 1979 (Box 53, Folder 3)
    - 1980 (Box 53, Folder 4)
    - 1981 (Box 53, Folder 5)
    - 1982 (Box 53, Folder 6)
    - 1983 (Box 53, Folder 7)
    - 1984 (Box 53, Folder 8)
    - 1985 (Box 53, Folder 9)
    - 1986 (Box 53, Folder 10)
    - 1987 (Box 53, Folder 11)
    - 1988-1989 (Box 54, Folder 1)
    - 1990-1992 (Box 54, Folder 2)
    - 1993 (Box 54, Folder 3)
    - 1994 (Box 54, Folder 4)
    - 1995 (Box 54, Folder 5)
    - 1996 (Box 54, Folder 6)
    - 1997 (Box 54, Folder 7)
    - 1998 (Box 55, Folder 1)
    - 1999-2001 (Box 55, Folder 2)
    - 2002 (Box 55, Folder 3)
    - 2003 (Box 55, Folder 4)
    - 2004 (Box 55, Folder 5)
    - 2005 (Box 55, Folder 6)
    - 2006 (Box 55, Folder 7)
    - 2007-2010 (Box 55, Folder 8)
    - posters, 1970s (Map-folder 41, Folder 3)
    - posters, 1980s (Map-folder 75, Folder 1)
    - posters, 1990s (Map-folder 75, Folder 2)
    - posters, 2000s (Map-folder 75, Folder 3)
    - undated (Box 55, Folder 9)
  - Subseries 6.2. Miscellaneous
    - Interviews [I1, I4], 1992,1993 (Box 28, Folder 8)
      1. 1) Berke, Joe c. 1993: Computer-generated transcripts of two parts of an interview between Joseph Berke and Schneemann, 7pp and 13pp, with extensive holograph revision by Schneemann. 4. Rebecca Schneider interview, computer-generated typescript with extensive holograph commentary by Schneemann
    - CS in magazines (Box 190, Folder 11)
      Heresies, Elima, Flash Art, High Performance, Meaning
    - CS catalogs - Early Work, Recent Work, Video Burn (Box 190, Folder 9)
    - Thomas McEvilley essay on CS, draft "What You Did Do", 2007 (Box 50, Folder 9)
    - Theses - Articles on CS (Box 45, Folder 9)
    - (oversize), 1960s (Box 41, Folder 2)
    - Works of Others [WOO1], 2005 (Box 28, Folder 9)
      Serra, M.M. and Ramey, Kathryn. Eye/Body: The Cinematic Paintings of Carolee Schneemann. 2005: Four typescript drafts of the essay, approx. 25pp each, each heavily commented by Schneemann.
  - Subseries 6.3. Separate chronological series, as described in bibliography
    The material in this group was assembled by Schneemann herself and is listed in a bibliography available here: http://purl.stanford.edu/fv281yr5961. There is likely to be substantial overlap between this subseries and the other two.
    - 1955-1969 (Box [1])
    - 1970-1974 (Box [2])
    - 1974-1977 (Box [3])
    - 1977-1979 (Box [4])
    - 1980-1981 (Box [5])
    - 1981-1984 (Box [6])
    - 1984-1987 (Box [7])
    - 1987-1988 (Box [8])
    - 1988-1990 (Box [9])
    - 1990-1991 (Box [10])
    - 1992-1993 (Box [11])
    - 1993-1994 (Box [12])
    - 1994-1995 (Box [13])
    - 1995-1996 (Box [14])
    - 1996-1997 (Box [15])
    - 1997-1998 (Box [16])
    - 1998-1999 (Box [17])
    - 1999-2000 (Box [18])
    - 2000 (Box [19])
    - 2000-2001 (Box [20])
    - 2001-2002 (Box [21])
    - 2002 (Box [22])
    - 2002-2003 (Box [23])
    - 2004-2005 (Box [24])
    - 2005-2006 (Box [25])
    - 2006 (Box [26])
    - 2006-2007 (Box [27])
    - 2008 (Box [28])
    - 2008-2009 (Box [29])
    - 2009-2010 & oversize (Box [30])
    - oversize (Box [31-32])
- Series 7. Publishing/book production
  Contains material concerning Schneemann's books, including correspondence with editors and publishers, drafts and galleys, catalogs, and other related files.
  - Subseries 7.1. Stiles/MIT/Imaging Her Erotics/etc.
    - CS interviews (Box 115, Folder 1)
    - Diane Cleaver "Imaging" proposals (Box 115, Folder 2)
    - Jay Murphy correspondence (Box 115, Folder 3)
    - misc. correspondence (Box 115, Folder 4)
    - Kristine Stiles, 2003-2004 (Box 115, Folder 5)
    - Kristine Stiles, 2005 (Box 115, Folder 6)
    - Kristine Stiles, 2005 (Box 116, Folder 1)
    - Kristine Stiles correspondence, etc., 2001-2002 (Box 116, Folder 2)
    - Stiles/Fluxus (Box 116, Folder 3)
    - CS Interviews (Box 116, Folder 4)
    - CS Interviews (rejected) (Box 116, Folder 5)
    - Vallie Export (Box 116, Folder 6)
    - CS Writing (Typed) (Box 116, Folder 7)
    - CS Interviews (Box 116, Folder 8-9)
    - Stiles, 2000 (Box 117, Folder 1)
    - Stiles, 1999 (Box 117, Folder 2)
    - Kate Haug (Box 117, Folder 3)
    - CS in Articles/Chapters (Box 117, Folder 4)
    - MIT Cuts & Connections (Box 117, Folder 5)
    - Annotated drafts, notes, etc. [unfoldered] (Box 118)
    - MIT catalogs, etc. (Box 119, Folder 1)
  - Subseries 7.2. More Than Meat Joy/McPherson & Co.
    - More Than Meat Joy (Box 113, Folder 2)
  - Subseries 7.3. Correspondence Course
    - Correspondence Course (Box 113, Folder 1-3)
    - Correspondence Course (Box 113, Folder 4-5)
  - Subseries 7.4. Vulva Morphia / Enter...Vulva
    - Enter Vulva (Box 119, Folder 3)
    - Vulva Morphia original edits, 1994 (Box 119, Folder 4)
    - Vulva Morphia Text, 1993-1994 (Box 119, Folder 5)
  - Subseries 7.5. Known/Unknown
    - Known/Unknown material (Box 119, Folder 2)
  - Subseries 7.6. Other books
  - Subseries 7.7. Misc.
    - book projects, other writing, undated, 1967-1972 (Box 112, Folder 11)
      Includes Parts of a Body House Book; Sexual Parameters Survey; American I-Ching Apple Pie
    - book projects, other writing, 1975 (Box 112, Folder 12)
      Includes Cezanne She Was A Great Pianter; Early & Recent Work (Documentext)
    - CS publishing (Box 113, Folder 1)
      Includes material about Cezanne She Was A Great Pianter, Vulva's Morphia, Up To & Including Her Limits, etc.
    - McPherson & Co. catalogs (Box 113, Folder 3)
- Series 8. Publicity
  Contains printed material publicizing Schneeman's art and projects, including press releases, exhibition catalogs, fliers, posters, pamphlets, programs, schedules, paid advertisements in periodicals, etc. Arrangement is chronological, with oversized material (mostly posters) filed separately.
  - 1956-1962 (Box 56, Folder 1)
  - 1963-1967 (Box 56, Folder 2)
  - The Bridge, 1965 (Box 56, Folder 3)
  - 1965-1966 (Box 56, Folder 4)
  - 1967 (Box 56, Folder 5)
  - 1968 (Box 56, Folder 6)
  - 1969 (Box 56, Folder 7)
  - 1970 (Box 56, Folder 8)
  - 1971-1972 (Box 56, Folder 9)
  - 1973 (Box 56, Folder 10)
  - 1974 (Box 56, Folder 11)
  - 1975 (Box 56, Folder 12)
  - 1976 (Box 56, Folder 13)
  - 1977 (Box 56, Folder 14)
  - 1978 (Box 56, Folder 15)
  - 1979 (Box 56, Folder 16)
  - 1980 (Box 56, Folder 17)
  - 1981 (Box 57, Folder 1)
  - 1982 (Box 57, Folder 2-3)
  - 1983 (Box 57, Folder 4)
  - 1984 (Box 57, Folder 5)
  - 1985 (Box 57, Folder 6)
  - 1986 (Box 57, Folder 7)
  - 1987 (Box 58, Folder 1-2)
  - 1988-1989 (Box 58, Folder 3)
  - 1990 (Box 58, Folder 4)
  - 1991-1992 (Box 58, Folder 5)
  - 1993 (Box 58, Folder 6-7)
  - 1994 (Box 58, Folder 8)
  - 1995 (Box 58, Folder 9)
  - 1995 (Box 59, Folder 1)
  - 1996 (Box 59, Folder 2)
  - 1997 (Box 59, Folder 3-4)
  - 1998 (Box 59, Folder 5)
  - 1998 (Box 60, Folder 1)
  - 1999 (Box 60, Folder 2-3)
  - 2000-2001 (Box 60, Folder 4)
  - 2002 (Box 60, Folder 5)
  - 2002 (Box 61, Folder 1)
  - 2003 (Box 61, Folder 2-3)
  - 2004 (Box 61, Folder 4-5)
  - 2005 (Box 61, Folder 6)
  - 2006 (Box 62, Folder 1)
  - 2007-2009 (Box 62, Folder 2)
  - undated (Box 62, Folder 3)
  - posters (small) (Box 157, Folder 1-4)
    Sorted approximately chronologically.
  - posters (medium) (Map-folder 158, Map-folder 159, Map-folder 160)
  - posters (large) (Map-folder 161)
- Series 9. Calendars, address books
  - calendars (Flat-box 126, Folder 1)
  - Address file, index cards & scraps [unfoldered] (Box 91)
  - address books [unfoldered] (Box 132)
    Some notes, decorations ,etc. Two appear to be some kind of account book.
- Series 10. Clippings/subject files
  Majority are from 1990s-2000s. Also includes some correspondence (especially printed out email), photographs, essays, and other printed material. Many articles are from the New York Times. Schneemann drew from these files as inspiration for her artwork.
  - New Palz Mall (Box 30, Folder 1)
  - Newspaper articles 1990s-2000s (Box 30, Folder 2)
  - Historic/local [NY state] (Box 30, Folder 3)
  - Yoko Sunday Mirror, 2000 (Box 30, Folder 4)
  - Palestine (Box 30, Folder 5)
  - Politics (Box 30, Folder 6)
  - Radiation (Box 30, Folder 7)
  - Orgasm (Box 30, Folder 8)
  - WTC (Box 30, Folder 9)
  - Disaster/catastrophe (Box 30, Folder 10)
  - Bird-snake etc. (Box 30, Folder 11)
  - Oil (Box 30, Folder 12)
  - Art (Box 30, Folder 13)
  - Analysis, War on Terror/biochemical (Box 30, Folder 14)
  - Afghanistan (Box 30, Folder 15)
  - Ecology (Box 31, Folder 1)
  - Gender (Box 31, Folder 2)
  - Humor (Box 31, Folder 3)
  - Mystical (Box 31, Folder 4)
  - Slaughter, foot & mouth (Box 31, Folder 5)
  - Image sources (Box 31, Folder 6)
  - Images exhibits, 2002 (Box 31, Folder 7)
  - Images [old prints] (Box 31, Folder 8)
  - Images, color copies (Box 31, Folder 9)
  - Ideas for visuals (Box 31, Folder 10)
  - Landscape (Box 31, Folder 11)
  - Guardian cover [with CS] (Box 31, Folder 12)
  - Jon Benet murder, 1997 (Box 31, Folder 13)
  - Woman (Box 31, Folder 14)
  - Women herstory research news (Box 31, Folder 15)
  - misc. (Box 31, Folder 16-17)
  - misc. images, old photos (Box 31, Folder 18)
  - misc. clippings (Box 32, Folder 1-3)
  - politics, 2001-2002 (Box 32, Folder 4-6)
  - politics, 2001-2002 (Box 33, Folder 1-5)
  - politics, 2001-2002 (Box 34, Folder 1-4)
  - politics, 2001-2002 (Box 35, Folder 1-4)
  - politics, 2001-2002 (Box 36, Folder 1-4)
  - misc. (Box 36, Folder 5)
  - magazines, art (Box 39, Folder 1-3)
  - magazines, politics (Box 39, Folder 4)
  - Middle East politics newsletters etc. (Box 39, Folder 5)
  - Animal clippings (Box 43, Folder 5)
  - Feminist articles (Box 111, Folder 2)
  - Middle East Report, 1981-1982 (Box 40)
  - magazines, art (oversize) (Box 41, Folder 1)
  - At War- Bosnia, Lebanon, Syria, 1999-2000 (Box 103, Folder 3)
  - Virtual-Cyber, 1999-2000 (Box 103, Folder 4)
  - Technical Info, 1999-2000 (Box 103, Folder 5)
  - Sex, 1999-2000 (Box 103, Folder 6)
  - Mythologies, 1999-2000 (Box 103, Folder 7)
  - Political/Lebanon, 1999-2000 (Box 103, Folder 8)
  - Local (NY), 1999-2000 (Box 103, Folder 9)
  - Jokes, 1999-2000 (Box 103, Folder 10)
  - Ives/Ruggles, 1999-2000 (Box 103, Folder 11)
  - Images, 1999-2000 (Box 104, Folder 1)
  - Health / Youth, 1999-2000 (Box 104, Folder 2)
  - Grief, 1999-2000 (Box 104, Folder 3)
  - Women, 1999-2000 (Box 104, Folder 4)
  - Friends, 1999-2000 (Box 104, Folder 6)
  - Gender Biology, 1999-2000 (Box 104, Folder 5)
  - Flora & Fauna, 1999-2000 (Box 104, Folder 7)
  - Ecology, 1999-2000 (Box 104, Folder 8)
  - Culture-Sensibility, 1999-2000 (Box 104, Folder 9)
  - Conspiracy-Politics, 1999-2000 (Box 104, Folder 10)
  - Brain-Nerves, 1999-2000 (Box 104, Folder 11)
  - Book-Research, 1996 (Box 104, Folder 12)
  - Black Issues, 1999-2000 (Box 104, Folder 13)
  - Biology, 1999-2000 (Box 104, Folder 14)
  - Anthropology, 1999-2000 (Box 104, Folder 15)
  - Americana, 1999-2000 (Box 104, Folder 16)
  - Alchemy Ritual, 1999-2000 (Box 104, Folder 17)
  - Aggression-Violence, 1999-2000 (Box 104, Folder 18)
  - Airline, 1999-2000 (Box 104, Folder 19)
  - Art Issues, 1999-2000 (Box 104, Folder 20)
  - Animal Ecology, 1999-2000 (Box 104, Folder 21)
  - Gender-Social, 1999-2000 (Box 104, Folder 22)
  - Pornography, 1999-2000 (Box 104, Folder 23)
  - Research Body/Gender (Box 111, Folder 6)
  - Pornography (Box 111, Folder 7)
  - Obscene (Box 111, Folder 8)
  - Film notes (Box 111, Folder 9)
- Series 11. Other artists
  Schneemann is a friend, supporter and collaborator with a variety of other artists (visual/media, performance, feminist, and many other) as well as poets, writers, dancers, filmmakers, composers, musicians, designers, critics, and scholars. This series consists primarily of printed material, including books, artist books, chapbooks, catalogs, exhibition notices, catalogs, magazines/journals/zines (covering art, literature, film/video, cultural studies), mail art, articles, essays & unpublished typescripts, etc. Please note that there is relatively little correspondence, and most original writing is confined to postcards, inscriptions, or other short notes. Schneemann also writes about some artists here, and annotates many of her books and magazines. Artists are also present in elsewhere in collection, particularly James Tenney, Clayton Eshleman, Anthony McCall, Stan Brakhage, Joseph Cornell, and the many artists in the Fluxus/Judson/NYC orbit.